Abhilasha Agrawal User Experience Designer

abhilasha.in@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/abhilashaagrawal abhilashaagrawal.wordpress.com +91-9971133270

I have 2+ years of experience in Design in domains of Marketing Automation, Tourism, Telecom operations & Energy Management.

Before design, I worked as an Application Developer in Telecom domain (Bharti Airtel Ltd.) for more than 2 years in Business Analytics & Optimization Portfolio at IBM India.

Education

Master of Computer Applications, Banasthali University, 2010

B.Sc. Honours in Computer Science, Banasthali University, 2007

Employment

Senior User Experience Designer,

User Experience Designer, Digital Dionysus, Delhi, October, 2015 - Present

UX Engineer, TargetingMantra,Gurgaon, April, 2015 - October, 2015

Application Developer, IBM India, Gurgaon, August, 2010 - March, 2013

Awards

Orion Award from **IBM India** in recognition of Eminence & Excellence

Skills

UX Skills Responsive Design, Problem solving, User Research, Wireframing, Rapid Prototyping, Paper Prototyping, User-centered design, User Research, User & Stakeholder Interview, Competitor Research, Personas, Use cases, Task analysis, Information design & architecture, Data-driven design, Scenarios, Card Sorting, Usability Testing, Product design, Experience Mapping

Visual Design Skills User Interface design for Web, Tablet & Mobile, Android App design, Logo Design, Brand Collateral design, Print production, Color, Typography & Typesetting

Creative Skills Calligraphy, Sketching, Painting, Photography, Illustration

Tools

Design Tools Adobe Creative Suite (Adobe Illustrator, Lightroom, Photoshop, Muse, Fireworks), Inkscape, Audacity, Final Cut Pro

Rapid Prototyping Tools Adobe XD, Sketch, inVision, Keynote, Antetype, Hype, Mural

Design Apps Adobe (Comp, Fix, Mix, Photoshop Sketch, Capture, Spark Page, Post, Video), Snapseed, Stop Motion, Animatic

Other Tools Wordpress, Google Analytics, Github, Unix Shell scripting

Certificate of Appreciation for Exceptional Work from the client Bharti Airtel Ltd.

Significant Projects

Digital Dionysus Corporate Website

Stakeholder Interviews, Requirements documentation, Information Architecture, User Interface Design, Use cases, User Experience, Responsive design, Design Guidelines

Digital Dionysus is a design consulting company. The project is about designing its corporate website.

- Conducted Stakeholder interview to gather content and design requirements
- Designed Information Architecture (IA) and use cases for the website
- Created production ready artworks for User Interface (UI)
- Designed Icon set for the website
- Created UI Design Guidelines document

Infozech Software, Digital Dionysus

Kickoff meeting, User & Stakeholder Interviews, Information Architecture, Persona, Task flow diagrams, Typography, Prototyping, Design Sprints, User Experience, Design Audit

Infozech is a leading provider of technology-led solutions that combines cloud-based technologies with a managed services approach to address ground-level challenges in telecom operations and energy management. The project deals with redesigning the enterprise software using user-centric approach.

- Conducted User and Stakeholder interviews to collect insights into the respective domain and to understand the business requirements
- Created design language for the Enterprise software
- Conducted design sprints sessions with the client
- Selected typeface for the enterprise software as well as for the corporate website
- Created Information Architecture , Personas and user Task flow diagrams
- Created design prototypes for the User Interface
- Conducted design audits for the client

Designrev.in, Digital Dionysus

Logo Design, Wordpress Blog, Design meetups, Print Production

A Design Revolution that aims to transform India through #PureDoing. The project demands designing a whole new ecosystem around design from Print production to User Interface Design to creating social media buzz

- Created final artworks for the Logo Design, along with Stress and Color testing and designed the alternative versions to fit in variety of situations
- Designed Wordpress Blog website
- Co-conducted design meetups
- Designed 'Design Sketchpad' and prepared final artworks for print-production
- Designed promotional Social media banners for Design Revolution from India

Whizkidz Media, Digital Dionysus

Design language, Android App design, Child psychology, Video Curation

Provides an app that presents a curated list of kids-friendly videos that enriches their knowledge and lets them explore the universe in their own way

- Understanding and communicating the child psychology for a better user experience
- Experienced interaction with the client while creating the design language for the app interface
- Demonstrated User interface design of app screens to the client

Loving Parent, Digital Dionysus

Logo Design, Brand Identity, Stress Test, Color Test

Parenting sessions that provide insights and creative solutions to children's undesired actions and behaviours. This initiative required a visual identity in the form of a logo with logotype that can connect and communicate the message to the audience effectively.

- Created Logo and the Logotype as the visual brand identity
- Conducted stress test and color test of the logo
- Created alternative versions of the logo to fit in a variety of situations and print environments

Ceebeecee, Digital Dionysus

Design Consulting, Brand Collateral Design, Print production, Presentation Design

Ceebeecee is an established travel and tourism company that offers Corporate Travel, MICE, Leisure Travel, Foreign Exchange, among other services. The project requirements included designing Brand collaterals and Presentation along with design consulting for an International Tourism Trade Show at Berlin

- Experienced interacting with business stakeholder while Design consulting sessions and contributed towards strategic planning for better client services
- Created artworks for brand collateral designs
- Designed presentation and brochures on Indian Tourism destinations for ITB, Berlin

Predictive Engagement Platform, TargetingMantra (now acquired by Snapdeal)

Product Design, Social Media Promotional Graphics, Iconography, Design Documentation

A US-based startup company that provided 'Omni-channel Personalization Suite' and 'Predictive Marketing Automation Platform' for ecommerce companies. The project dealt with designing the product and its various features; along with conceptualizing creative ideas and designing for various marketing initiatives

- Conducted Stakeholder Interviews to gain insights into the product and business requirements
- Conceptualized creative ideas for the user-interface for various product features and for many marketing initiatives
- Designed visual mockups/ prototypes from wireframes and delivered final design production-ready assets for development
- Collaborated with multidisciplinary teams like development team for the implementation of designs as per the guidelines and with marketing team to coordinate on marketing activities and policies to promote products and services